<idea-plugin require-restart="true">
    <id>com.github.magneto3572.spotyy</id>
    <name>Spotyy</name>
    <vendor email="magneto3572@github.com" url="https://github.com/magneto3572/Spotyy">magneto3572</vendor>

    <description><![CDATA[
      <h2>Spotyy — Spotify Controls + Team Music in Your IDE</h2>

      <p>
        Stay in the zone. <b>Spotyy</b> embeds Spotify playback controls directly into the JetBrains
        status bar and lets you see what your teammates are listening to — all without leaving your editor.
      </p>

      <p><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/magneto3572/Spotyy/main/src/main/resources/screenshot/screenshot3.png" width="600" alt="Spotyy — Listening nearby, Focus Room, Ghost mode"/></p>

      <p>
        <b>Note:</b> Requires the Spotify desktop app to be installed and running.
        Playback controls work on <b>macOS</b> (via AppleScript) and <b>Linux</b> (via D-Bus / MPRIS2).
        The Spotify web player is not supported.
      </p>

      <hr/>

      <h3>Playback Controls</h3>
      <ul>
        <li><b>Play / Pause</b> — toggle playback instantly from the status bar</li>
        <li><b>Previous &amp; Next track</b> — skip or rewind without leaving your IDE</li>
        <li><b>Volume slider</b> — click the volume icon for an inline popup slider; auto-dismisses after 5 seconds</li>
        <li><b>Now Playing</b> — live artist and track name in the status bar, refreshed every 3 seconds</li>
        <li><b>Adaptive theming</b> — icons and colours automatically match your IDE's light or dark theme</li>
        <li><b>Zero performance impact</b> — all Spotify communication runs on background threads</li>
      </ul>

      <hr/>

      <h3>Team Music (Local Network)</h3>
      <ul>
        <li><b>Listening nearby</b> — see who on your network is currently playing music and what track</li>
        <li><b>Vibe match</b> — get notified when you and a teammate are listening to the same song or artist</li>
        <li><b>Focus Room</b> — start a shared countdown timer (25 / 45 / 60 min) and invite teammates to focus together; the host can remove members at any time</li>
        <li><b>Nearby room visibility</b> — even if you haven't been invited, you can see that a Focus Room is running on your network, who's hosting it, how many members are in it, and how much time is left</li>
        <li><b>Ghost mode</b> — hide yourself from the network so no one can see what you're listening to; automatically locked while you're in a Focus Room</li>
      </ul>

      <hr/>

      <h3>Getting Started</h3>
      <ol>
        <li>Install <b>Spotyy</b> and restart your IDE.</li>
        <li>Open the <b>Spotify desktop app</b> on your Mac and start playing a track.</li>
        <li>Open any project — the Spotyy widget appears automatically in the <b>bottom status bar</b>.</li>
        <li>Click the <b>👥</b> or <b>✦</b> button in the status bar to open the team panel.</li>
        <li>Use the playback buttons to control music and the volume icon to adjust level.</li>
      </ol>

      <hr/>

      <h3>Requirements</h3>
      <ul>
        <li><b>macOS</b> 10.15 Catalina or later — or — <b>Linux</b> with D-Bus (any modern distro)</li>
        <li>Spotify desktop application (installed and running)</li>
        <li>Any JetBrains IDE: IntelliJ IDEA, Android Studio, PyCharm, WebStorm, CLion, GoLand, Rider, and more</li>
        <li>All users on the <b>same local network</b> (office Wi-Fi, shared LAN) to see each other</li>
      </ul>

      <h3>Permissions</h3>
      <p>
        <b>macOS:</b> On first launch, macOS may ask for <b>Automation permission</b> so the IDE can control Spotify.
        If the widget shows no track information, open
        <b>System Settings → Privacy &amp; Security → Automation</b>
        and enable Spotify access for your IDE.
      </p>
      <p>
        <b>Linux:</b> Spotify is controlled via the standard D-Bus MPRIS2 interface — no extra permissions needed.
        Optionally install <code>playerctl</code> for more reliable metadata parsing
        (<code>sudo apt install playerctl</code> / <code>sudo dnf install playerctl</code>).
      </p>

      <hr/>

      <p>
        Found a bug or have a feature request?
        <a href="https://github.com/magneto3572/Spotyy/issues">Open an issue on GitHub</a>.
      </p>
    ]]></description>

    <change-notes><![CDATA[
      <h2>0.0.5</h2>
      <ul>
        <li><b>Linux support</b> — Spotify playback controls now work on Linux via D-Bus / MPRIS2; Spotify is auto-launched if not already running</li>
        <li><b>First-run onboarding</b> — OS-aware setup walkthrough shown on first launch; guides you through installing Spotify, playerctl (Linux), and granting Automation permission (macOS), with one-click copy commands</li>
        <li><b>Light mode UI fixes</b> — button hover color and separator are now theme-aware; no more black hover flash in light mode</li>
        <li><b>Progress bar on theme switch</b> — progress bar no longer disappears when switching between dark and light themes</li>
        <li><b>Vibe match midnight reset</b> — vibe match counter now resets at local midnight based on system clock</li>
        <li><b>macOS: ~/Applications detection</b> — Spotify installed in the user Applications folder is now correctly detected</li>
        <li><b>macOS: Automation permission alert</b> — shows a notification if the IDE is blocked from controlling Spotify, with instructions to fix it in System Settings</li>
      </ul>

      <h2>0.0.4</h2>
      <ul>
        <li><b>Nearby room visibility</b> — non-members on the same network can now see active Focus Rooms: who's hosting, how many members are inside, and time remaining</li>
        <li><b>Focus Room</b> — shared countdown timer (25 / 45 / 60 min); host can invite peers and remove members at any time</li>
        <li><b>Listening nearby</b> — see teammates on the same network and what they're playing</li>
        <li><b>Vibe match</b> — highlights when you're listening to the same song or artist as a teammate</li>
        <li><b>Ghost mode</b> — hide yourself from the network; automatically locked while in a Focus Room</li>
        <li><b>Broader IDE compatibility</b> — supports IntelliJ 2022.3+ and Android Studio Giraffe and later</li>
        <li><b>Popup layout fix</b> — peer panel now renders at a consistent fixed width on all machines</li>
      </ul>
    ]]></change-notes>

    <depends>com.intellij.modules.platform</depends>

    <resource-bundle>messages.MyBundle</resource-bundle>

    <extensions defaultExtensionNs="com.intellij">
        <statusBarWidgetFactory id="com.github.magneto3572.spotyy.MyStatusBarWidget"
                                implementation="com.magneto.spotyy.statusbar.MyStatusBarWidgetFactory"/>
        <postStartupActivity implementation="com.magneto.spotyy.startup.MyProjectActivity" />
        <notificationGroup id="Spotyy" displayType="BALLOON" />
    </extensions>
</idea-plugin>